<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Musings of a Junior Dev</title>
    <description>Blog and portfolio site | Angela Riggs</description>
    <link>angelariggs.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="angelariggs.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 09:09:36 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 09:09:36 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, interwebs! I’m Angela - it’s nice to meet you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s that? Oh, of course - I’d be happy to tell you a bit about myself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been in Portland for almost two years now (July 1st will mark the happy occasion of our move from Florida), and currently hang my hat in St. Johns, along with &lt;a href=&quot;http://joshriggs.net/&quot;&gt;Josh&lt;/a&gt; (my husband) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/p/sL96HQFL82/&quot;&gt;Frank&lt;/a&gt; (our adorable puppins).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before May, I was a teacher with an awesome cohort of 3-5-year-olds; my days revolved around reading, science and math experiments, and hugs. I still love hugs, but I’m changing my career path and becoming a JavaScript developer. I’m one month into a Full-Stack Javascript bootcamp at Portland Code School, and I love it! Some of the projects I’ve created are a calculator, an old-school text adventure game, and a static-site generator; and I’ve already had my first struggle with &lt;a href=&quot;https://storify.com/angelariggs/imposter-syndrome&quot;&gt;imposter syndrome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m finding that, at its best, coding is exciting, creative, collaborative, and fun. And when coding is at its best, it’s also challenging, scary, and stubborn. It’s all a part of the whole, and I’m really excited to be a part of it!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>angelariggs.github.io//2015/05/30/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">angelariggs.github.io//2015/05/30/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
