<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Angela Wilson Riggs</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://angelariggs.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="http://angelariggs.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Junior Developer - What Does it Mean?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I stumbled onto an interesting Twitter conversation the other day, and I&amp;#39;ve been looking forward to continuing my thoughts in a broader form here on my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversation in question revolved around the use of titles for developers, and what those titles actually denote or communicate about the person who holds a specific title. The meaning behind dev titles was especially unclear when it comes to the role of a &amp;quot;junior&amp;quot; developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I see a job posting with the word &amp;quot;junior&amp;quot; in them, I don&amp;#39;t always know what that says about the company&amp;#39;s expectations - but I know what it means to me, and I hope that the company&amp;#39;s meaning comes close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, &amp;quot;junior&amp;quot; indicates a level of responsibility, rather than a level of skill or experience. As a junior developer, I want to have code reviews and possibly pair programming throughout the week, to help strengthen my coding knowledge and best practices. And &amp;quot;best practices&amp;quot; refers not only to my coding methods, but also to the workflows and processes that differ from one company to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathys-potestio.com/want-to-be-a-developer-where-to-start-and-what-to-expect/&quot;&gt;code school graduate&lt;/a&gt; and current dev intern, I know that there are many things I don&amp;#39;t yet know. But when considering my classification as an employee, should my experience in development be the only experience considered? In addition to my 9 months of dev work, I have years of client-facing experience with high communication and problem-solving skills, and I was a teacher for three years. Don&amp;#39;t these skills and experiences add value to my role as a developer? Being able to communicate clearly with clients, or share knowledge with colleagues would seem to be valuable assets to bring to a tech company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with the ever-changing nature of technology and development work, tying the definition of &lt;em&gt;junior&lt;/em&gt; specifically to dev experience can get kind of shaky. For instance, let&amp;#39;s say that a JavaScript developer fresh out of bootcamp gets hired at a .NET agency, looking to branch out into other technologies. In terms of overall years of dev experience, that bootcamp graduate could be considered a junior. But when that .NET company starts working on their first JavaScript project, that same bootcamp graduate is the resident expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;#39;ve talked about what the junior title means to me, and why it can be a tenuous thing to define. What does it really mean to tech companies? It&amp;#39;s one thing to read about tech stacks in a job posting - but how does the title of &amp;quot;junior&amp;quot; set a company&amp;#39;s expectations of work, and how do they communicate those expectations?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject of job titles has been a recent topic of conversation here at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metaltoad.com/&quot;&gt;Metal Toad&lt;/a&gt;, especially in relation to career paths. As a developer (junior, staff, or senior), what really are the expectations for developers at each level? And if these expectations aren&amp;#39;t set transparently and clearly, how does a junior dev set goals to complete for becoming a staff developer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We asked, and our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metaltoad.com/people/matthewgarthmcluckie&quot;&gt;Director of Development&lt;/a&gt; answered! Matthew and our dev team leads worked together to create a career matrix for junior, staff, and senior developers. The matrix includes expectations for all areas of life as a Toad: teamwork habits, programming, methodologies, and vision &amp;amp; passion. And while I might like to see some of the items expanded on with more specific criteria for success, most of the descriptions are written with enough detail that I can set and meet goals for advancement, and understand the expectations of my responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, let&amp;#39;s look at &amp;quot;Pairing and Code Reviews&amp;quot; for junior, staff, and senior. The career matrix sets the expectations for each developer level. Junior devs are expected to participate in code reviews and pairing; staff devs are expected to initiate pairing and code reviews, and to offer substantive feedback that contributes to their peers&amp;#39; growth; senior devs are expected to lead code reviews and communicate best practices, enforce review coverage as stories are closed, and take lead in following up with a bug ticket when peer review uncovers a significant issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For programming, the career matrix addresses coding, software design, QA &amp;amp; testing, debugging, environment configuration, DevOps, and security. I can easily understand a junior developer&amp;#39;s responsibilities for each of these areas, and see where a junior dev would need to improve their skills and strengths in order to advance. The matrix that Metal Toad created takes away the murkiness and frustration of standard job titles without standardized expectations, and replaces it with clearly defined responsibilities and expectations that allow developers here to set goals for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Has your tech company created or communicated definitions for its developer roles? Share your dev title definitions, or what you&amp;#39;d want to see!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog post was inspired by a conversation on Twitter with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/realntl&quot;&gt;Nathan Ladd&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kwuchu&quot;&gt;Iheanyi Ekechukwu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://angelariggs.github.io/junior/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://angelariggs.github.io/junior/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Knot of Toads</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just finished my first week as a toad!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started my internship at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metaltoad.com/company&quot;&gt;Metal Toad&lt;/a&gt; on Monday. I had been expecting an October start, but Randi - their wonderfully exuberant Director of People - asked if I could start earlier. So a few weeks earlier than expected, I hopped (get it?) on the Yeon Building elevator and pressed the orange toad button for the 4th floor!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by diving into the documentation - getting to know all of the bits and pieces of setting up at workstation at Metal Toad. After spending a few hours doing the process longhand, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cesar-jimenez.com/&quot;&gt;Cesar&lt;/a&gt; let me in on a script that one of the other devs wrote, that installs pretty much everything I&amp;#39;ll ever need. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an intern, my workload will likely be split about 50/50, between QA for various client projects, and working on an internal project. I started QA for a client project on my first, so I got to experience setting up my local environment for a Drupal project. My dev lead, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metaltoad.com/people/slavko&quot;&gt;Slavko&lt;/a&gt;, walked me through the process and explained everything. (Thinking of future Angela, I took notes on it all and typed it up on Google Drive.) After I got the project set up, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metaltoad.com/people/jordan&quot;&gt;Jordan&lt;/a&gt; got me started with testing. I spent some solo time working with Behat, getting practice writing tests. After a couple of hours of Googling and Stack Overflowing, I did some troubleshooting with Jordan and we realized that my tests &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; have been passing. We think it was something with the version of Behat that I was using. So I started looking into &lt;a href=&quot;http://unitjs.com/&quot;&gt;unit testing for JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;, since my interest is in front-end, and I&amp;#39;ll start putting it into practice on another project next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also resolved a JIRA ticket, and made my first Git commit on a project! I had some downtime from the first project, so Cesar directed me toward another project that had some front-end work to do. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/kgiardchase&quot;&gt;Kyle&lt;/a&gt; found me a JIRA ticket that needed front-end work. I used my notes from the project setup with Slavko earlier &lt;em&gt;(thanks, past Angela!)&lt;/em&gt; and set up the environment for the new project. I dove into the Sass files to fix some padding issues across a few of the site pages, and then - and this is the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; moment of triumph - I committed my changes to the repo without breaking anyone else&amp;#39;s code! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first week has been &lt;em&gt;such&lt;/em&gt; a fantastic experience! I realized that the people who work at Metal Toad are more than just colleagues - they&amp;#39;re a family. They work together, but they also respect each other and want to help everyone succeed. Everyone has work of their own, but they all made time to stop and answer my questions, or to direct me toward the person who could. They have a Slack channel dedicated to shoutouts, and they use it every day. I got a round of applause from the team at my first code review. Day by day, everyone has made a point to introduce themselves to me individually and ask how I&amp;#39;m doing in my first week. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m so excited to a part of the Metal Toad family, and I can&amp;#39;t wait to see how the next four months begin to unfold!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://angelariggs.github.io/first-week/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://angelariggs.github.io/first-week/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting Down the Dev Path</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Developer bootcamps are popping up all over the U.S., and Portland is no exception. We have no less than five code schools, including one focused on online courses. With so many options and opportunities, how do you know what’s right for you? And when it comes to committing your time and money, how do you make sure that you take a viable path?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Career or Curiosity?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t start out as a developer—my background is in education. Until I enrolled in a JavaScript immersion course, I taught a wonderful cohort of preschool kids in North Portland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved the creativity and challenge of teaching, and helping my kids develop their hearts and minds. But for various reasons, I realized that I needed a change—a different kind of challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband Josh, a UX designer, used to joke that I would make a good front-end developer because I have an eye for design, but I also love rules. As I began to look at other careers, I considered development. Because of Josh, I’d met a lot of people in tech, and really appreciated the friendliness and creativity of the community as a whole. Plus, I always like learning new things (this will be important later), and coding seemed like it would offer the creative challenge that I wanted in a career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with Treehouse’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamtreehouse.com/tracks/front-end-web-development&quot;&gt;Front-End Dev track&lt;/a&gt;—and I liked it a lot. I began looking into my options for learning code, and found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.portlandcodeschool.com/&quot;&gt;Portland Code School’s&lt;/a&gt; Hack + Help. I signed up and went to the next meetup, where I talked with Al, the instructor for their Web Foundations course, and Stacy, a recent graduate of their evening JavaScript course. I ultimately signed up for Web Foundations, a seven-week evening course which covered HTML, CSS, and some JavaScript and jQuery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the seven weeks, I was hooked! I enjoyed the collaboration, creativity, problem-solving, and the challenge of learning new things every day. I had decided—I wanted to be a developer. Now I needed to figure out how to make that happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Choosing a School&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the code schools in town have scheduled open houses, and I would definitely encourage potential students to go. If you’re on Twitter or Facebook, follow the schools’ accounts for information on classes or meetups. When you do meet with instructors or staff from a code school, ask about internship possibilities, or job placement. I’d also recommend going to local tech meetups, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pdxwit.org/&quot;&gt;PDX Women In Tech&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.womenwhocode.com/&quot;&gt;Women Who Code&lt;/a&gt;—you’re almost certain to meet current or former code school students, and it’s a great opportunity to get feedback from a recent graduate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another factor is choosing a coding language—JavaScript, Ruby, Python?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some schools, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://pdxcodeguild.com/&quot;&gt;PDX Code Guild&lt;/a&gt; and Portland Code School, offer single-language courses, whereas &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.epicodus.com/&quot;&gt;Epicodus&lt;/a&gt; covers three in its JavaScript-focused courses. Look at job postings, talk to the schools, find out what skills are in demand. If you want to learn more about a language before committing to a course, take a workshop or short course on Treehouse first to get familiar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I had already taken the Web Foundation course there, I started looking into Portland Code School’s JavaScript Immersion course. I talked to students who had taken the course, and with one of the directors about the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also met with instructors from PDX Code Guild and went to an open house at Epicodus, where I met with instructors and students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In researching the different code schools, I had three main considerations: class format, cost, and job placement. I liked the smaller class sizes offered at Portland Code School and PDX Code Guild, compared to the larger classes at Epicodus. I was leaning toward JavaScript for my coding foundation, which put Epicodus and Portland Code School at the top of my list. Epicodus won out in cost, but the smaller class size at Portland Code School was ideal for my learning style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The Code School Experience&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember how I said that learning new things was important? As a developer-in-training, you will be learning new things every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every. Single. Day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe that reminds you of your time in school, where you learned new stuff all the time, right? This is different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one thing, the average bootcamp student has been out of school for a few years, which means you’ve lost all those good study habits. Secondly, you’re not just working your way through the times table. Almost every day of the course, you are learning a completely unfamiliar concept, and applying it to completely unfamiliar work. You’re learning a new language, new logic, and a totally new way to think. And you’re expected to create with this knowledge at the same time you’re trying to learn it. We called it “drinking from the JavaScript firehose.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really hard. You’re going to work your butt off, and it won’t be easy. You’ll feel frustrated, and like you just don’t get it. The frustration? Get used to it. Frustration means you’re learning something new, and that will never go away. As a developer, you are always trying new things, iterating on how you work, finding different tools or frameworks to use. It’s okay to feel frustrated, but it’s really important to let it motivate you to learn, rather than block you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling like you’re falling behind while everyone else moves forward? That’s imposter syndrome, and everyone that I’ve talked to in the tech community has dealt with it. I’m sure that it exists in every career field, but it’s a constant topic of conversation in the tech scene. The good news is, since everyone has experienced imposter syndrome, people are also &lt;a href=&quot;https://storify.com/angelariggs/imposter-syndrome-55ce4fba1fdd573c4de09933&quot;&gt;willing to help out&lt;/a&gt; when they see someone else going through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because bootcamps are so fast-paced, you probably won’t have time to finish every project that you start in class—I strongly urge you to continue the projects on your time, in the evening or on weekends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two benefits. The first is more time with the code. It’s always good to get more practice in, and to have some time where you have to do it on your own. This builds your resourcefulness—knowing where and how to find the answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second benefit is that you’ll have finished code to look back on for future lessons and projects. To this end, you should always comment your code! Commenting your code is another way to make sure you understand what your code is doing, and helps you build the ability to explain it to someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in learning to code, a bootcamp can be a great choice. They take a relatively short amount of time, especially considering other options for a career change. But a lot of it is up to you—to do the research, and to commit all of your time and energy to learning these new skills. If you’re not sure about a career as a coder, try out some evening intro classes or online courses. Never be afraid to ask questions. Ask about the school and the curriculum; ask former students what they liked or didn’t like about their experience; and always ask for help when you need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tech community is big, and there are so many possibilities out there—take the time and figure out what’s right for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RESOURCES&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Code Schools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.portlandcodeschool.com/&quot;&gt;Portland Code School&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.epicodus.com/&quot;&gt;Epicodus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codefellows.org/locations/learn-to-code-in-portland&quot;&gt;Codefellows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pdxcodeguild.com/&quot;&gt;PDX Code Guild&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/&quot;&gt;Treehouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Meetups&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Portland-Code-School-Learning-and-Development-Group/&quot;&gt;Hack + Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://calagator.org/&quot;&gt;Calagator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pdxwit.org/&quot;&gt;PDX Women in Tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.womenwhocode.com/portland&quot;&gt;Women Who Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Mentorship-Saturdays/&quot;&gt;Mentorship Saturdays&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Jobs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://portlandtech.org/&quot;&gt;Worksource Tech Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://angel.co/portland/jobs&quot;&gt;Angel.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published for &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathys-potestio.com/want-to-be-a-developer-where-to-start-and-what-to-expect/&quot;&gt;Mathys + Potestio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://angelariggs.github.io/codeschool/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://angelariggs.github.io/codeschool/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Final Countdown</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I write this, I&amp;#39;m entering into the second week of capstone projects at Portland Code School. The lectures are done, although the learning continues, as we use our knowledge of full-stack JavaScript to build our own web apps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My group consists of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pub/nathan-brenner/b3/b25/652&quot;&gt;Nate&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/cpoff&quot;&gt;Curt&lt;/a&gt;, and myself. We went though the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.portlandcodeschool.com/webdevelopmentprimer/&quot;&gt;Foundations Course&lt;/a&gt; together, and our learning and collaboration styles work well together. I&amp;#39;m really happy that we all agreed to work on the web app that I proposed - it&amp;#39;s been cool to see it taking shape! We&amp;#39;re building a site called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nathan-j-brenner/snapOR&quot;&gt;snapOR&lt;/a&gt;. As a hiker and photographer, I spend a lot of time going between different websites to look up cool hikes, and researching the kind of photos that people have taken there. Wouldn&amp;#39;t it be nice to have all of that information - hikes and photos - in a single website? Our web app is the answer to that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re using Jade, Foundation, and Backbone.js for front-end; and Orchestrate.io for the back-end. We have some Express server happening, but a lot of it&amp;#39;s going to be in Backbone, since we&amp;#39;re creating a single-page app at the suggestion of our project advisors, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/smashdevcode&quot;&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kenhowardpdx&quot;&gt;Ken&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csgpro.com/&quot;&gt;CSGPro&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;#39;re using APIs from Google Maps, Oregon State Parks, and Flickr, and we&amp;#39;ll add in Weather Underground if we get to Version 2! This project has really helped me bring together my code knowledge from the two months of class, and I&amp;#39;m really proud to be contributing to the front-end and back-end work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I&amp;#39;m digging into Backbone. My grasp of it is still shaky, and I&amp;#39;ve spent part of my time trying to find coherent tutorials on using Backbone for a single-page app. It&amp;#39;s slowly coming together, and I have a feeling that most of my time this week will be devoted to understanding and building with Backbone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that note, it&amp;#39;s time to dive back into the wild world of Backbone - wish me luck! (And if you have any resources that helped you learn Backbone, please send it my way! You can tweet me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/angelariggs_&quot;&gt;@angelariggs_&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://angelariggs.github.io/final-countdown/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://angelariggs.github.io/final-countdown/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tweeting for Community &amp; Understanding</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m halfway through my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.portlandcodeschool.com/javascriptimmersion/&quot;&gt;developer bootcamp&lt;/a&gt;, filling my brain with JavaScript and preparing to transition my skills out of the classroom and into a job. Along the way, I&amp;#39;ve been collecting resources: documentation libraries for Orchestrate and jQuery, tutorials like &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Developer&amp;#39;s Network&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/&quot;&gt;Treehouse&lt;/a&gt;, and oodles of bookmarked pages for projects and tips. There are an enormous number of resources out there, and they cover every aspect of development that I could want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, one of the most helpful resources has been the least technical in nature—Twitter. Twitter is way more than a place to share GIFs and the hip place you went for lunch. It&amp;#39;s a tool for creating relationships, and I&amp;#39;ve found it to be a valuable resource for a range of things, from technical knowledge and troubleshooting to engaging the local tech community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Twitter for Troubleshooting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first few weeks of my immersion course, one of our daily projects was to get familiar with various commands for GitHub. We pulled and committed and merged until we were comfortable enough for the cursing to stop, and then we researched some less common uses. One of these was “committish”, which sounds like a developer&amp;#39;s idea of a joke. I tried several different resources, but couldn&amp;#39;t really find a coherent answer—so I took to Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tagged some developers that I know, and asked them what “committish” really was. In about 20 minutes, I&amp;#39;d heard back from two developers that I know, and they&amp;#39;d given me better answers than I was able to find online myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Twitter for Networking&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Portland&amp;#39;s tech community offers so many ways to make connections—meetups, networking events, and a variety of conferences. I went to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://act-wpdx.splashthat.com/&quot;&gt;first conference&lt;/a&gt; as a developer because someone I followed was tweeting about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an amazing and inspiring experience, and I connected with some of the speakers on Twitter afterward, as well as with people I met during the lightning talks and breakout sessions. I became familiar with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pdxwiit&quot;&gt;PDX Women in Tech&lt;/a&gt; because a company that I follow on Twitter was hosting a networking event for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject of TypeScript came up in class recently, and I mentioned it to my husband, Josh. He happened to be following someone on Twitter who had just started a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Portland-TypeScript-Meetup/&quot;&gt;TypeScript meetup group&lt;/a&gt;, so he connected us with an introductory tweet. Now I have a resource for learning about TypeScript, and connecting with other developers in the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Networking on Twitter can also lead to interviews and jobs. I often see &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SDStowe/status/610394014542639104&quot;&gt;hiring managers&lt;/a&gt; and current employees tweeting about job openings at their company. Sometime last year, Josh connected on Twitter with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/komejo&quot;&gt;developer named Joe&lt;/a&gt;, who was new to Portland. They met up for beer and conversation, and continued their acquaintance on Twitter. When ThinkShout was hiring a web developer a few months later, Josh recommended the position to Joe, and in turn, recommended Joe for the position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, you&amp;#39;re reading this article because of a connection I made on Twitter! I followed Mathys+Potestio to participate in their Great Resume Debate of 2015. The panel suggested using social media to add context to who you are as a potential employee, and afterwards I had a few more questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick, Mathys+Potestio&amp;#39;s community manager, had me email him so we could continue the conversation. We met up and had a great talk about social media and transitioning into the tech community from another career path, which led to this very blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Twitter for Community&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of all, I&amp;#39;ve found Twitter to be a fantastic tool for creating relationships with people in the tech community. During my first week as a JavaScript student, I went through an enormous attack of imposter syndrome. All of the little challenges that come along with a new way of thinking were adding up, and my struggle seemed insurmountable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went home that day feeling like I&amp;#39;d failed, and made the wrong choice in becoming a developer. I reached out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/derickbailey&quot;&gt;Derick&lt;/a&gt;, a JavaScript developer that I follow on Twitter, and basically asked if it was normal to feel frustrated and challenged like this. He responded and reassured me that it was 100% normal—that he, and all developers, feel this way all the time because they&amp;#39;re always learning new things. He was incredibly encouraging—not just about tackling JavaScript, but about being able to get over the block and ask him about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our conversation made such a big difference in my outlook for learning, and I&amp;#39;ve become more accepting of the challenges I come across, because it means I&amp;#39;m learning something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Window to the World&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter is probably the only place where following someone you don&amp;#39;t know is an acceptable thing to do! Were you inspired by a speaker&amp;#39;s ideas at a conference? Tweet a quote that resonated with you, or let them know how much you enjoyed their talk. Is there a company that you would love to work for? Follow them to see what they&amp;#39;re talking about and what&amp;#39;s important to their staff. Then reach out to someone at the company who does what you want to do—ask them to meet up for coffee or beer to talk about their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like &lt;a href=&quot;https://jsfiddle.net/&quot;&gt;JSFiddle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;, Twitter is a tool for developers. You can use Twitter to solve a code problem that&amp;#39;s got you stumped, or celebrate a coding triumph (all of your merges to GitHub worked!). You can reach out to people and organizations for networking, or find a meetup group that&amp;#39;s involved with something you want to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The foundation for all of these experiences on Twitter is building relationships—being able to connect with people across town or across the world; reaching out to start a conversation and create a relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter describes itself as “your window to the world”—so throw open that window and start building!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published on &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathys-potestio.com/a-developer-tweets-to-build-community-and-understanding/&quot;&gt;Mathys + Potestio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://angelariggs.github.io/tweet-article/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://angelariggs.github.io/tweet-article/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>JavaScript Jokes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I look at each day of learning JavaScript, it can be really hard to recognize how much I&amp;#39;ve learned since this course started. But then I realize that just five short weeks ago, this interaction on Twitter would never have happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;storify&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;//storify.com/angelariggs/coder-s-got-jokes/embed?header=false&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://angelariggs.github.io/jokes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://angelariggs.github.io/jokes/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, interwebs! I&amp;#39;m Angela - it&amp;#39;s nice to meet you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#39;s that? Oh, of course - I&amp;#39;d be happy to tell you a bit about myself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been in Portland for almost two years now (July 1st will mark the happy occasion of our move from Florida), and currently hang my hat in St. Johns, along with &lt;a href=&quot;http://joshriggs.net/&quot;&gt;Josh&lt;/a&gt; (my husband) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/p/sL96HQFL82/&quot;&gt;Frank&lt;/a&gt; (our adorable puppins).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before May, I was a teacher with an awesome cohort of 3-5-year-olds; my days revolved around reading, science and math experiments, and hugs. I still love hugs, but I&amp;#39;m changing my career path and becoming a JavaScript developer. I&amp;#39;m one month into a Full-Stack Javascript bootcamp at Portland Code School, and I love it! Some of the projects I&amp;#39;ve created are a calculator, an old-school text adventure game, and a static-site generator; and I&amp;#39;ve already had my first struggle with &lt;a href=&quot;https://storify.com/angelariggs/imposter-syndrome&quot;&gt;imposter syndrome&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m finding that, at its best, coding is exciting, creative, collaborative, and fun. And when coding is at its best, it&amp;#39;s also challenging, scary, and stubborn. It&amp;#39;s all a part of the whole, and I&amp;#39;m really excited to be a part of it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://angelariggs.github.io/welcome/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://angelariggs.github.io/welcome/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>